You know consumer fireworks can add fun and excitement to any holiday event or gathering at parties.
I am Captain Joe Bruni with over three decades of firefighting and emergency medical service experience.
What we're going to talk about is personal protective equipment when it comes to using common consumer fireworks.
Someone designated as the shooter should always be outfitted with a good pair of fitting safety glasses and a good fitting pair of light leather gloves or cloth gloves to avoid burn injuries.
Also no open toed shoes or bare feet should be permitted with anyone that is using consumer fireworks or designated as the shooter.
Even something as simple as the common sparkler can cause significant burn injuries.
The things like bare feet and unprotected hands.
Things like the common sparkler burn at a very high temperature from eleven to eighteen hundred degrees.
Common consumer fireworks emit showers of sparks which are very hot.
So it's a good idea to protect not only the user but the person who's a responsible adult designated as the shooter.
With safety glasses and some type of foot and protection and covering.
I'm Captain Joe Bruni stay safe and we'll see you next time.